Armando Urquiola Cabrera Full Stack Developer

me@urquiola.dev • (+49)151-41-4444-64 • Berlin
GitHub • LinkedIn • urquiola.dev

Executive Summary

I am a junior developer in new technologies, currently enrolled in a FullStack Software Development Diploma and actively pursuing an entry into the tech industry. Although I have programming experience with technologies and programming concepts, I have recently decided to upgrade my knowledge to increase my skills with the use of new technologies as modern development frameworks and Agile concepts. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, PHP and Object Pascal. I have 16 years of experience in IT customer services. I am a valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem solving ability. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

Education

February 2023 - August 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland -

(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

September 2004 - Dec. 2005 M. Sc. Botany, specialisation Bioinformatics

University of Havana, Cuba

September 1994 - July 2000 Diploma in biology, thesis with use of numerical methods

University of Havana, Cuba

Technical Skillset

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Object Pascal

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, Interbase, Firebird, Ms SQL Sever

Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js

Version Control: Git, Github

Portfolio projects

- 1. The last book page A full Stack site for managing a social network for reading, which allows you to comment on readings, bookmark books for reading lists and follow people on the site and give them likes. Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript and React in the frontend. Python, Django REST framework and Postgres DB in the backend. Cloudinary and Heroku for hosting and deploy. GitHub https://github.com/patchamama/PP5-drf-api-The-last-book-page
- 2. Bookstore Loans Full Stack application to manage book loans: reservations, loans, extensions and returns. It also allows commenting on books and check the availability in a bookstore, or in a public or private library. Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap and JavaScript to the frontend. Python, Django framework, Postgres DB in the backend. Cloudinary and Heroku for hosting and deploy. GitHub https://github.com/patchamama/PP4-Bookstore-loans
- 3. Gutenberg On Mail The aim of the programme is to develop a tool that allows interaction from the terminal with the Project Gutenberg book catalogue, making queries and allowing the selection of books that can be sent by email to a given address. Technologies Used Python, google cloud platform, google spreadsheed api and Heroku for deploy. GitHub https://github.com/patchamama/PP3-GutenbergOnMail

4. Simple video-podcast generator - The objective of this program is to provide a visual tool to manage, test and check the position of the images to be added to an audio to make a video (with the sequence of images selected in the time defined by the user). Technologies Used - HTML5 , CSS and JavaScript. GitHub - https://github.com/patchamama/PP2-Simple-Video podcast-generator

Work Experience

February 2023 - Present Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland - (Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

August 2006 - December 2022 STRATO AG International Service Contact Center

Second level customer service and support agent, Berlin, Germany

- IT consulting for customers in the areas of server administration (windows server and gnu/linux with plesk), online shops (epages and prestashop), cloud computing (hidrive) and web hosting (CMS: wordpress, joomla, drupal and moodle)
- Development of internal team applications for task management, kanban and use of clippings
- Support customer queries efficiently and accurately, via telephone, email or chat and clients escalations
- Identify customer needs and help them to use or develop specific functions
- Analyse and report product malfunctions and create and update FAQs
- Optimisation/monitoring/analysis of loading speed/capacity with performance audit tools
- Website content analysis and SEO review with rankingCoach
- As second level, management of team tickets and training of new team members

December 2005 - August 2006 Reintegration of life in Berlin, Germany

- German language learning, integration course, gastronomy services and salsa teacher
- Developer support of "living collection management" software for the national network of botanical gardens in Cuba

June 2004 - October 2004 Botanischer Garten und Botanisches Museum, Freie Universität, Berlin

Software programmer

- Development of a Microsoft SQL Server database with map integration for the "Flora of Cuba" project
- Programming of a Firebird/Interbase driver for BioCase software in python

Sept. 2000 - December 2005 Botanical Garden, Pinar del Río, Cuba

Network administrator / Software programmer

- Network management with Debian GNU/Linux on server and windows workstations
- Webmaster of the Botanical Garden's portal (joomla)
- Programming of application in Borland Delphi 5 and Interbase 6 DB for the "registration and management of the flora of Pinar del Río" with emphasis on endangered and medicinal plants (Award-winning software)
- Creation, training and support of client/server software in PHP, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery, XML, HTML and CSS for the "management of living collections" in botanical gardens. The application is actually used in the national network of the botanical gardens of Cuba (was part of my master's project)

Interests/Additional Information

- Hobbies: chess, cycling, tracking, playing guitar and piano, philosophy, meditation, dancing salsa and forró
- Fluent Spanish and B2 level in English and German